On welcome and thank you for coming.
Raise your hand at this is your first-time available.
Welcome you picked a really good when it comes to lots of exciting things
being announced today and for those of you that it's not your first-time welcome back I'm
...from the windows engineering team and today I have with me jeff
arnold design lead from the windows team.
In this session we're going to cover everything you need to know about building your universal windows application.
Thank you for your ongoing feedback and your participation in this conference as well as with the
windows insider program the feedback that you've been giving to us it's really helping
...directly influencing how we build windows
ten and it's and it's a bunch of stuff that we're going to cover in this talk today what we've heard from meal is
...you wanted enhanced flexibility of the design interaction model on windows when
you're building your apps we'll talk about that today for those of you who have historically
...for windows as well as for windows phone you
asked for us to reduce the device specific work that's even more important now as
your applications will be running across even more devices in addition you asked for those of you
who have invested in other platforms for the ability to reuse your designs in your
code on windows are happy to say that you can do that as well.
Please...evaluation form at the end of the session.
In this session will be focused primarily on
phones tablets laptops and desktop pc
...design considerations that go along with us however that is not the extent of the
reach of the windows universal platform.
Soon these apps will be running on small I ot devices hollow
...the xbox big-screen in your living room and even the surface have.
We're going to cover a lot of information here today some of the high-level and some of it more detail but
...that you can find everything we talk about as well as much more information on the
design that windows dot com site.
If it jeff is going to walk us through the design patterns for navigation
commanding content but first let's take a look at what exists
in the platform that makes it easy to design one app
...adapt to many form factors.
When we set out with a vision to create system
when app could run on a vast array of device form factors as well
as input methods we knew we needed to abstract as much of that from the app development
processes possible we want you to be able to focus on building your app
and making a great?
We thought hard about the most impactful scenes
...differences across these various one factors and we want to share that thinking with you today.
First of all window...screen size given that your application is going to be running on many
form factors a great app is one that will take advantage of the various screen sizes
a sizes increase you can fit more content on the screen and as what your users will...
We also have to consider supporting various, various input methods your users
maybe using mouse keyboard touch ten or even
a game controller so it's important to have a way to think about that and
optimized for one handed use in those cases also it's important to know that your app the
user can be using your app in different ways...across the different form factors on a phone
user maybe using the app more for content consumption whereas on a desktop pc
may be using that same at for content creation so knowing how to adaptor...process form
...important that's a lot to consider and we wanted to make it easy
for you to take advantage of the thinking so we've done a lot of the heavy lifting and we're
going to go through those pieces now.
First of all...heard this before microsoft has created
ecosystem of devices all running the same operating system.
What this enables is that your application can target a wide range of devices?
The platform easily allows you to adapt this one design across one factors and
of course you could always taylor that experience should you decide to do so.
To make this possible we created unify api set across windows
...windows phone to abstract many of the differences between these devices.
We have also rationalize the common control sets between windows,
windows phone into one set of controls that are
optimized to work on a range of sizes as well as input method.
You don't have to start at square one you can use these building blocks that already exist and
...have intelligence built-in such as scaling in reacting to these input methods and
when you use these controls your app will...work correctly without much effort on your part?
Here's an example that shows the evolution convergence of the app
are so let's take a look back in windows eight-point...this is what the app
are looked like it could be placed at the top or the bottom of the screen.
It contained all the elements both primary and secondary commands in one place the number of
items was gated based on the width of the screen it was running on and we showed the icon labels
as well this fr was usually hidden by default and that's just something to remember for a moment.
Take a look back at...on a point one app are.
This was a piece of ey that was always located at the bottom of the
sound to optimize for one handed usage the maximum number of actions that
...is...and overflow actions were hidden
behind a dot-dot-dot menu when pressed the app...with slide up in the
at menu items which show to conserve space in the rest face
...the rest area the icon labels were hidden by default as well.
In windows ten we wanted to create to build a control that provided the flexibility
of the windows eight-point one app are with the design considerations of the phone eight-point
one app are what we built for windows ten is a true hybrid of its predecessors.
It can be placed in multiple positions on the screen.
And, the number of items that contains is based on the width of the screen that's running on.
Let's look at this in a couple of examples in this case the
...place at the bottom of the big-screen.
When dot-dot-dot overflow is
...the at many rises up into the space where you expected to the?
We decided to keep this at
menu just to a portion of the screen versus going across the whole screen because it...kinda...
when it was across the whole screen and you also notice we brought for the windows phone model of having the
icon labels hidden by default to conserve space give more space for your application to run.
In this case this command...the top of the screen and the right thing just happens
when the dot-dot-dot overflow is...the out menu comes down.
And, here on the smaller size screen.
We have optimized for one handed usage by always keeping at the bottom
...dot-dot-dot is press you see the out menu at this point we
...go full...so that your some can reach them and you just fine.
All right so we talked about how the coming controls scale across
the form factors what's now...on to talking about input method.
Some of the controls will react directly to how they were
...in this example for the context many what you see on the left is that this
control was invoked.
when that context control context many opens you'll see that the items listed already density
level appropriate for mouse interaction so the items are a little tighter?
What you see on the right is that same context many running on the same exact device that when
invoked via touch same menu items
appear but they're much more spaced out so this is all handled and
Ok,
here's another set of controls across the whole control set with universal windows apps
the controls include the appropriate for this is necessary for the different
input methods so the pivot control from windows phone continues to work the way that it did
on windows found however we're now bringing this to the desktop and when we do if
you're users using a mouse...come up to allow the user to
click-through the various pivots you also see these...showing up on a date...
As well as all of the controls so it's great that the common controls
...this input method but what if you in your application
have features functionality or commanding that you want to change based on
input method we have you covered there's well there's a new api the universal windows
app platform enables you to listen to the dominant input method of a given device and
...uruguay again you're not required to do this
common controls do it you can choose to do in your app if you would like.
So, far...cover the unify api set.
As well as a converge common controls
any input methods let's keep going though because we're not done.
We're introducing a concept called effective pixels effective pixels
are pixel units which are independent of a given device.
Simply put effective pixels enable
you they allow your application to visually scale from...
and simply put they allow you to designer application to a base resolution and then
are scaling algorithm takes over it applies the viewing distance the
typical viewing distance of a given device because we all know that you hold phones quite close
your facebook when you're looking at xbox screen it's very far away source scaling algorithm
will apply the appropriate viewing distance as well as pixel density
and optimizes the ui for perceived size rather than actual size this can be a
complex topic at first so I have a video for you that will watch?
And, see if it makes more sense.
Here we have a you element that's one hundred by one hundred.
Some one hundred point text and some twenty-four...text.
...studies ui elements been...pc...tablet...
The screen to compared side-by-side elements on the pc and tablet seem larger than
elemental the one hundred by one hundred ui element displays...one hundred by one hundred physical
pixel from one hundred-fifty by one hundred
fifty physical pixels on the tablet and two hundred by two hundred pixels on the pc.
These devices...different screen sizes viewing distances and pixel density
...when you take into account...viewing distance reach device elements all...perceived...
This enables you to use the same element size and type brand for all devices.
And, that in a nutshell is how display scaling and
...pixels...designers and developers from having to consider pixel density and viewing distance.
So, we're really excited about this scaling algorithm we think it takes a ton of
the work abstracted from the app development process and we could talk a
long-time about effective pixels...we have a lot more content to get...I'd like to direct you to
a theater presentation that's happening just down the hallway it's happening three times today
tomorrow and friday and eugene one of our design integration leads from microsoft is
going to be going through the details on what effective pixels are and why you should care?
So, while effective pixels allow you to scale your app visually from screen to screen
something else that you can use effective pixels for our break points are screen widths
intersected pixels...opportunities for new layouts.
For instance three hundred-twenty effective pixels is a small-screen.
That windows battleship on we built a common controls for this size and
...and generally when your app is in this mode and is running at three
hundred twenty effective pixels either phone or a small window on the desktop
it supports one...of content like a message list...from email?
...of seven hundred-twenty effective pixels is a common point or apps...to move to
...panes of content if that makes sense for your application.
This will be prominent on windows tablets as well as a five-and-a-half finch
babbitt device turned into the landscape orientation and we
know that are users expect much more functionality as that those pixel sizes increase.
And, lastly there's another break point at ten...effective pixels this is a
break point where can make sense to move two-a-three...layout if it makes sense for your application.
To see what this looks like in practice here's an example of the
mail app running at these three different break points in the smallest window you cone
...of content which is just the message less.
As a screen gets larger and we move up to seven hundred-twenty effective pixels we move to a to
...layout botha message...as well as a preview...
And, then third when we get to ten twenty-four effective pixels we now have the account and folder
list the message list of preview
...is a really good example of taking advantage of those break points.
The reality is you get to decide if you listen to these break points and then what
your app does...various...
So, as hissing here there's already a really strong foundation laid to enable you to designer
app to run across form factors let's move forward and learn how to
designer application using the universal windows app patterns to
...us through these please welcome jeff arnold design...from windows.
Ok, so, now that we've seen a number of things that the system and the platform are going to do on behalf of
utwo at help you in developing your app they're...take a look at some things that design
wise you should to take into consideration every application is going to be made up of
three discrete elements versus the content microsoft...lead but the
monitor of content over chrome for the last of releases and it's no different now this is
the bread-and-butter of all of your applications so you really want your content to stand out more than anything else
second is commanding or a way of taking action on the content.
And, third as a way to navigate to different sections of the content.
So, when choosing your navigational pattern there's some considerations to
take into account first priority of navigation?
Just because you're application may be...and deep doesn't mean that necessarily
that your users constantly changing to different sections of your app
...that for therefore it's okay sometimes if let's say like you know,
the navigation is out of reach of one handed u take the size of device into account
again on a smaller device one how to use is often very important but then on
larger size devices you have plenty of room to fit in as much content as possible and
...high-level navigation and really make the app as useable as possible.
To optimize for content layout the navigational pattern that you choose
can inject ad a hierarchy on the page content of your page so
you should choose a navigational pattern that is appropriate and is
...to the and works along with the content that's on the page?
Molasses primary and put method some of the...some of the navigational patterns that we
have work better for mouse and keyboard and others are just more delightful when use with touch.
So, I want to start before I get into the navigational patterns that we
had a want to say that there's no single required pattern as part of windows ten
we want you to go out and we want you to innovate as much as possible on windows we have done
is we did was we went out and we did an audit of all the conventional patterns that are out in
the world today regardless of the platform that they're implemented
on we make sure that there's a way that there that you can bring your apps to windows and use them.
The patterns we're going to talk about
here pivots tabs hub master detail and the hamburger pattern.
So, pivots is probably the most iconic controls that we had on windows phone so of course
there available here...platform for folks that don't know-how pivots work
there's a string of headers they go across the top of page in order to change from section
to section the user just simply swipe sauna body content and the content...swapped out.
If I apply the considerations that I talked about earlier dependents...work something like this
pivots allow for frequent access to expose navigation...always at the top of
the page user can see them and, I always access them because of the way pivots
work that works well on both large and small screens but because of the flicking left
and right navigation it works really well for one handed uses you look at your phone devices
...optimized for content layout the
pitted header works really well to set up the hierarchy of your page.
So, it's just the user knows when...come to the page that this is the top...everything just
...long stream lakes with the pivot controller ok because as the string likes become longer
the pivot just bleeds off to the right and as you swipe demand then you can see the complete titles.
Because of the nature of this horizontal navigation you...avoid using controls inside of the
...control that also have their own horizontal navigation
this kind of leaves the user with inconsistent experience inside of
their app now the pivots work well with pretty much all in-put methods but
are most delightful...with...that's why we created...windows phone to begin with.
Over the years we found through user research...it's really better to have no more than six
pivots at a time because any for any number of pivots above six
the user becomes disoriented they start losing track of where they are inside of your app.
As we do began to evaluate pivots on the larger screen we
start to see a little bit too much motion with the
care selling behavior of the pivot header itself plus the body content so we decided to do is
...something new.
At the point that all of your pivot headers fit on a given page...the pivot header now
locks in place and now the pivot will take on a more tab like functionality and
consequently this also is like more appropriate for these larger screens where the mouse will be used.
This also doing just brings us to our second pattern which is tabs we recommend that
you actually build your tab ui using...pivot control you
simply re style the headers that are inside of the pivot in the control take care of everything else for you.
A is also recommended that you have no more than five tabs on the screen at a time
this is the largest number of tabs that will fit on the smallest screen that windows phone will
ship on and still reach the minimum hit target for those tabs.
So, the
...the considerations for tabs is very similar to pivots with a
couple's slight differences tabs are very good for instances where muscle memory
is important so let's say I have a dial...and, my user knows that
the voicemail tab is the second tab they can always come there they all they...now
is just tap on number two and it's always in the exact same place regardless of the layout.
...phrase far sized device the tabs work very well on large and small screens but typically
have a larger footprint and pivot so that's something to keep in mind because of the traditional layout
of tabs typically an icon over a string of text typically is higher than just
the string only visualization on pivots...pushes the content down so just keep in mind what
...visualization of your tabs due to the layout?
Delight pivots the tab set up a clear page hierarchy and
it does work well for all in-put methods.
So, the next the next pattern is hub I'll go through the considerations for this if you
want to go see a more deeper dive into a practical application of
...the hub across all the devices you want to attend...talk on friday
So, the...another could pattern that we had on windows phone
and it allows you to access a lot of content all at once typically the way this work
...a lot of there's a number of sections across the
...each of those sections...contain a preview of the content they lived inside of that
...allowing the user to see what...what they were
with dissection kind of held before they really had a deep dive...to get to all of the content
...maximizes the use of the real-estate very well and works very well for one handed
use because it's just like pivots that uses the same flicking gesture.
Keep in mind...the hub is not really the best used for coed
...consumption...sorry it is best use per consumption app
data typically the user kind of browsers through the content like a storefront it's not
use not well utilized if you have an...you just want to get stuff done or
a user just wants to get to their content typically the hubble inject an extra page of
...level of hierarchy that just kinda gets in the way of what the user actually wants to get
too the
...as primary input methods the hub works very well with touch it works very well with game controller.
The next password pattern we'll be pretty much familiar to anybody that's ever
...client...master detail.
The way master detail works
...typically a list wvu on larger screen on the left-hand side with us bunch of
items as soon as you tap on one of those items the right-hand side which is the detail
painters updated to show that content
as this pattern gets shows up on the smaller screen these two these
two layers end up getting stacked on top of each other so when you tap on an item on the list you're actually
drill down to the content layer and then you have to utilize the back button to go back up.
For consideration here the bastard detail navigational pattern is a way of navigating
the content is already on the page you could actually...this to inside of one of the other
navigational patterns it's you don't necessarily need to but this one works well for that.
...because of the way it takes advantage...screen real-estate being side-by-side
on the large-screen and the having the drill behavior on the small-screen it-would
takes advantage of their screen real-estate very well and it works very well with all in-put methods as well
last pattern to talk about here is the hamburger pattern this pattern
...specifically...to brought to windows because we want you to be able to
...apps directly from other platforms and it's actually been one of the most
ask for patterns over the last couple releases of windows.
As we look at the considerations for hamburger
we'll see that the hamburgers really kind of a double-edged sword on law and large
screens it works well because you can either because by...pay the navigational
...can be expanded by default leaving all the navigational elements
...and what the user can see they can obviously fine however as the screen
sizes reduced typically what happens is the hamburger or the pattern is reduced down to
just the hamburger which as we know...has
...decreases engagement inside of your app this may be okay as long as
...needs to access that navigation infrequently?
Another the...and also because of the conventional position of the hamburger up in
the top left-hand corner doesn't work very well for one handed
use but again that may be okay as long as access to this navigation...infrequent and
...wealth pretty much other than one handed it works well for all in-put methods.
If I take a step back and take a look at this msn app say this is
actually a good example of how to use the hamburger pattern as you can see on the right-hand side when
...larger screen the pain is...is expanded by
...giving access to these higher-level navigational elements but the content that
the user really has access to is all in that right-hand...where that with the pivots where the
...all the content actually lives as you look at the smaller screen?
The pattern is reduced down to the hamburger it's okay because
a you typically don't need to access that hamburger all of the content is still
...built into the on page pivots that...that are already right there on the users finger.
Another example want to show the new outlook on mobile app.
Again, and, say this is a good use of the hamburger understand...
Educated the behind the hamburger is the folder view for this given mail application
...typical users...yet between ten to twenty emails a day and they live
...in-box they don't need to do a bunch of
switching of folders so it's okay that hamburgers and up in the left-hand...out of in out of
use what's important is that the content and the actions that you can take on the
content or down at the...screen and underneath...finger.
So, when we decided to bring the hamburger pattern to windows we decided we wanted
try a few things to see if we can make it unique to windows so the first thing
we did is we...to test a couple different...the first one we came up with
was called the home berger was just something unique...just difference we
want to status if we could change the hamburger into something else that people would say like
all that's the windows way of doing it the second was to use the app
icon we figured this would be a way of killing two birds with one stone like the app
could brand itself and the user would know that they could go up there to
navigate the app of course we had to test the hamburger?
So, the way we do testing is we test against personas so a
personas a representational user that has criteria that
basically fits...set of our user base and for this testing we tested with hope and
Hope is an eighteen-year-old college student because of her age she had her
probably her first real device that she had was a smartphone it probably had a touch-screen
...given this is probably why I like the her...her chest actually turned out very well no matter what
icon we put in play in front of her she knew exactly
what to do she's used to the touch paradigms and just assume that anything
...attach universes touch...then we go and we look at john.
John's a forty-year-old guy and he actually has way more of a
back story than you would think you would need to test software the researchers got really into this guy but the
partners information about him is he's four-years-old he's probably
...through every interaction paradigm that microsoft has ever come up with
...very occur custom to using the mouse and keyboard so when we put the icons in front of him
...a completely different story with the home burger and with the app icon he failed
it most of the task that we put in front of them however when we tested with the hamburger we were actually kinda
surprised.
He didn't he didn't succeed at every single task that we put in
from but he did this he did was able
...I'm sorry he was able to accomplish most of the tasks that we had put in front of them
so because of this we decided to stick with the traditional conventional hamburger icon.
The second thing we wanted...the location of the hamburger as, you know, in most applications
...the top left-hand corner of the screen we wanted to try and take a look at
the process of the problems that we're having on mobile where it's
doesn't work very well for one handed use so we want to see if we could move
it some other place and on the screen where the user could get to it easier.
Thepretty much the results came back pretty similar to the to as the icon results what
it up happening was anywhere any other position of the hamburger reduced
engagement in the app and actually didn't work out that well so with a new split view
...which is the control...implement the hamburger pattern is...we recommend
...the top left corner and uses the conventional three stripe hamburger icon.
So, the next thing...talk about is commanding right now in windows tanned there's two different ways to take
action on your content is a context menu and the command bar.
Context menu
as a common control the can be applied to any ui element that you would want to take action on.
It could be invoked by either right click with the mouse or press and hold for touch because
of the hidden nature of the this entry point we would recommend that you probably not put any
actions inside of the context menu
is not surface somewhere else in the app we don't want to leave
...user with a dead-end where they don't know where to us perform...very specific task.
The...control that we have in place now is the command
bar carmine kinda talked about this one a little bit earlier the new command
bar can be place at the top or bottom of the screen we recommend
that you place at the bottom of the screen on mobile devices for one handed u.
In windows eight there was one app...place apply across the bottom of the screen and it spanned all the
pains inside of that app is sometimes confusing when you has an item selected
...if the commands that...action on where adhere to that item or
...item in a different pain because of this we're suggesting that you can actually...our app
are command bar to add to multiple panes inside of your app so as you can see here
it's very clear which actions are associated with the list view and which
...which actions are associated with the...at the details pain?
Command...is limited to the amount of the actions
they can fit on the screen for screen real-estate we still recommended you probably have no more than
for primary actions like if they really kind of doubt that you have
too many apps they have
twelve primary things you can do on a specific object on your app like usually your app you want to
focus in on the one thing that app is there and really good about so
those secondary tertiary actions could be hidden underneath the dot-dot-dot fly out menu.
So, the last thing I'll talk about here's content.
I would argue that the way we have that you can refer content
and windows ten is no different than what you've already been doing on your websites and
ionization actually for your scaling of windows windowed apps on windows up to
this point in order to talk about the techniques here we've kind of...them as the six
...these are resize re
flow reposition reveal re architect and replace
now go through some design considerations for this however if you want to see how to implement
these insiders animal you want to attend tim...her...tomorrow it to p.
So, the first technique I'll talk about is resize this one's very simple you know,
pretty much any simple text editor will do this as long you have word
...turned on...so it is just a single column of content
is scaled appropriately to the size of the device or the window that lives in as the
...the size of the device
...the windows reduce the content just raps inside of it.
The second technique is re flow...not too different from the previous one except what
...had...starters two columns of content in the first
pattern is gets reduced down to a single column as a screen sizes reduced.
The third technique will be reposition.
We all know that your app can be made up
of multiple sections of content that are just laid out throughout the screen.
With reposition we have content we have column sorry section a and section
b when the screen...size first...to be reduced section a reduces
and width however once you reach a snap point let's say under seven hundred
twenty effective pixels and the you don't have enough room to fit
the content side-by-side the content and snaps to a new layout where
...becomes vertically scrollable.
If...were more real example this is
the app detail page from our store you can see how the items get
re flowed from the desktop screen to the mobile screen...
in you prioritize the content as it slows down on the mobile device.
The next technique is reveal now this isn't necessarily a way of handling your content
but making sure you're doing the appropriate thing for your app so this is a food
...finder app so if I'm
if I'm at work or I'm on my at home on my on my tablet
there's certain things I might want to do with this app like I want to I would want to access to all the food tracks that
are my area see some popular...maybe have favored some things are...
a schedule of the things are going to be around me some a really kind of plan where I want
to go however if you look over to the left-hand side you see on the mobile app
we replaced the favorites with a check you're doing the right thing here.
By swapping out between favorites and check in because when you're at
that food truck you can actually slow you can chap on the checking tab
...appropriate information and check in and let people know where you've
...what you've eaten and gainer give a rating center
...you know, rating to all your friends out there this is doing the right thing for your device this is
tailoring your app to make sure that is taken advantage of the like the
sensors and all the technology that's inside of the different devices.
So, the fifth technique here...architect this is what used by the master detail pattern that
I talked about earlier as I said before on the larger
devices the master detail fits side-by-side with the list view and the detail
...however as a screen sizes reduced the only the list
...visible and you have to drill...in a navigate via back button.
As you can see here this is how it works with an are people out.
So, the last the last technical talk about here is replace.
Device context within the device context you may want to have a different
type of navigation that is more suitable to device that your on as you can see here
...our photos app we take advantage of the hamburger pattern on the larger screen
what this does is it leaves a lot of extra space for the beautiful content on the right-hand side
...the smaller footprint of the hamburger on the left as screen sizes reduced and you look at
the that the phone side we've said is more important these the all of
...sections be accessible the one hand and therefore
they're using pivots in this instance.
This is another way that you can take advantage of the real-estate
and do what's appropriate for the device you can choose to use the hamburger you can choose to
use pivots across the full range however you may want to just make
sure make decisions around like what is the best
...the device so that you're putting the appropriate navigational pattern on each of devices?
So, what we've seen in this session is what the system and the platform are doing to help you and
developing your app we've also talked about how to handle navigation commanding and
content?
So, we're...do for the...session we're going to open up for some qa.
And, then be sure to visits design theater for some of our design sessions.
if you like...can standardsplease walk up to the microphones inside of the aisles.
Are a transitions part of the vocabulary
...for the hague and transitioning on a scream when you go from
...sm between some of the states are?
Are you talkers...in the context of transitioning on one device between
screen us between sizes yes, that should be here that is handled on the hague
...which we live today?
Hi, I notice that the new start menu has some three-d transitions
for the lifestyles and I was wondering if the two-d paradigm of windows
eight is kind of getting supplemented with some three-d loves so,
yes, we're looking at some new interesting a facts and just ways of.
Augmenting...was the old system so we can evolve it and we you know,
we're trying out.
The...paradigms to see like what works well in this new system.
Great thank you.
Yes, the question is from an asset perspective and images you have to provide images for
every single device that the answer there is that.
We have different scaling platters in the system that are all very well-documented
the reality is if you if you provide a very high-resolution image we
will just go ahead and use that to down scale to the other devices and it will look fine there are certain
situations and there's a talk tomorrow on the new continuum for found...you
...keno today so on that you'll be able to our...a desktop monitor with your
phone...so if you only included it really small assets on the phone you would want to consider in
that case specifically including hire asset
...images because it will be displayed on a big-screen but for the most part of
channel by the system given what you provide.
Yes, so, you can talk about the can the command
bart on with the app are previously...sleight down from the top so reserves
...recommend away now to have command bars come and go.
...so without...we're actually recommending that there on the screen by default so with windows a
recommendation was they were hidden by default and that was really to give more
and visibility to the content that was on the screen what we found was there
...some usability issues with that people aren't we sure how to find the hidden gesture
...everyone's neither heads yes...so we...
you we listen and now with windows ten of those command parser on the screen in fact
...best practices wise like just always put stuff on the screen eating your users to interact with.
With the master detail set up where your commended when you get
until phone you switch to drilling down to the details.
Is there mechanism...to make that easy to do or this on
...to be manual?
So, I...that might be a good question if you have attend
...needs talk tomorrow they would have some...to go to the expert lounges well
there's some folks there will have some good recommendations on how to achieve that.
We're designers moi.
Provides...sizes.
Not necessarily so it's more about the resolute question a
serious repeat the question the question was when you're providing icons for...
for the applications how many of those icons and different sizes you need to provide
and again that visual scaling happens within the system itself however there
are certain cases where you're if you're if you're writing, you know, and, targeting the
phone specifically know that the phone will be able to project to a big-screen so think about the assets
...provide it's really up to you whether you provide one set
at high-resolution images or whether you provide multiple sets to be optimized?
The question is if you provide multiple asset sizes does the does the system handle
showing the appropriate ones...the answer's yes.
...please regulates
that microphone if you can thank you for the as further webcast.
...for vector graphics like
sg is something like that to avoid the different.
Well, what I do not believe
at this moment again I think that's more of a technical question you could bring up to one of the folks in the experts
The three-g as one of those ones I think that we have been
...for quite a while and it's just one of...things in a backlog that we just haven't got to yet.
It's well-known that that's one that people want.
I am study to bring up images again but if I think about the assets and if I think
...is an app and I have a background image...five background images and
if I have to provide hd dissolution for all of them are very high-resolution
...by an...this I'm afraid that the app size would actually
increase to ready large one and then, you know,
...could be a problem because uses been...download the app itself.
Is there are...process behind what you would recommend
...I think there's a lot that sounds like there's a whole bunch of questions about that and I think what we'll do is
we'll head to that windows insider lounge tomorrow we'll make sure between now and then
that we get a good answer for that definitely hearing folks that sounds like a concern?
Hi, just want-to follow up...these imaging questions...actually a pre-recorded build talk from
steve right who talks about this in great depth talks about if you want to provide one
...should be...to which to should you pick etc and he also talks about things like
...asset...so in your particular case if you
had five different versions of the same asset windows will download the most appropriate one for the device
...so they won't waste a lot of disk space a lot of bandwidth downloading
...they can use so look online-only pre-recorded talk from steve rights wr
...http on scaling...thank you...tour.
How's that work for I'm sorry the question is how does it...for when js and.
That one actually as a question...up earlier...to follow-up on that we have been working with the when
js team as...same as we've been working with resemble team this release I am I
...like ninety nine percent certain that will be handle the exact same way but I just I to go
...to go back and check it to make sure that is true.
You should you should actually go talk to...gavel off out here he's one of our design integrator
is and he's going through the effective pixels...his session...a session tonight at seven in the
theater where you can ask questions like that he would probably address person...answers for that?
Photoshop I'll we are working on right now we have illustrator and I think we're working on
the photoshop layouts they'll be uploaded to the...windows dot com website.
All right there pretty obviously some business applications that are sufficiently complex another patterns
that you have shown would encompass what the interactions you would need to do sure what
you're thinking on trying to find where that where that line
...where you start stepping outside these
establish patterns and start to design a custom pattern for a specific at because of
its complexity or other considerations I mean like I don't think that the app has to get
all-day complex for you to try and evolving just do something different like I said like
the patterns that we have here that we presented today or those conventional patterns that are already out there so we
want to put those out as a starting point for you know, as you get into things like...be and,
those type of applications the thing
...remembers like we've kind of windows ten we kind of level set we started with what we
headers...we had the windows phone controls and we had the windows controls we
had to combine those into a single set so now we have a baseline and we're going to
start building back up from there so a lot of these controls that you use for like an lb
...more complex apps as we see folks trying to do new things with those then
we'll start to provide new tools to help you along the way for that but,
it's I don't think it has to...has to do with the complexity of the app to say like I
...do something different?
...ahead on africa just another...make the point, you know,
we're pretty prescriptive in windows...about the guidelines and what we...more
...and...and with windows ten what we're saying is you guys know your customers bass,
you know, you're, you're apps for requirements the vast
so bring your bring your code to windows and do what you need to do and there's a ton available on
a platform for you to do that but where you need to come up with something new or any pattern totally
appropriate to...
And, we and also like I was one of it like I think you've heard all
day want to reiterate though like we want all the feedback around the controls that we have today
...how you're actually using them and
...falling short so I guess my team kind of develops for like the next kind of drop
...common controls we want to be able to make sure that we're doing the right thing so that when you
dragnet control onto your page...the next time...actually provides
...experience that you are looking for to begin with we want to be able to like the allow you to tailor with these
controlsthe way you see fit as well.
Okay, great will be up here for a couple minutes if you want to come up and ask the question will also be in the
windows insider lounge tomorrow at eleven thirty thank you so much bigger.